Guide to the Roger M. Adelman Files of the John W. Hinckley, Jr. Trial, 1981-1989 MS2358
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Roger M. Adelman Files of the John W. Hinckley, Jr. Trial
1981-1989
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Knight, Paul
Cardozo, Mike
Adelman, Roger M.
MS2358
10.5 Linear Feet
Roger M. Adelman (1941-2015) was the senior prosecutor for the United States attorney's office during the trial of John W. Hinckley, Jr. The records, ranging in date from 1981-1989, are related to this trial and Hinckley's attempted assassination of United States President Ronald Reagan in 1981. In 1982, Hinckley was found not guilty by reason of insanity. In 1984, in direct response to the Hinckley verdict, Congress passed the Comprehensive Crime Control Act, which set a higher bar for the insanity defense in federal courts.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Paul L. Knight and Michael H. Cardozo, 2016 June 10 (Accession 2016.086)
Arrangement
Organized in 2 series: Legal documents and Personal writings.
Biographical
Roger M. Adelman (1941-2015) was the federal government lawyer who led the unsuccessful prosecution of John W. Hinckley, Jr., in the 1981 assassination attempt of United States President Ronald Reagan. The trial led to significant alterations in the law regarding the insanity defense in criminal trials. Prior to 1984, defendants could be found not guilty by reason of insanity if it could be shown that, because of mental disease, they could not tell the difference between right and wrong or could not control themselves well enough to obey the law. In 1984, in direct response to the Hinckley verdict, Congress passed the Comprehensive Crime Control Act, which set a higher bar for the insanity defense in federal courts. Under this new law, lack of control was no longer a defense.
Roger M. Adelman was born on June 25, 1941, in Norristown, Pennsylvania. He earned his bachelor's degree in English at Dartmouth College in 1963 and received his law degree from the University of Pennsylvania in 1966. Adelman then went on to serve in the United States Army and attended its language school in Monterey, California, to learn Russian. After leaving the military, Adelman began working for the United States Attorney's office in Washington, DC. In 1997, the Council for Court Excellence awarded him the Justice Potter Stewart Award for his contribution to the administration of Justice in Washington. Roger Adelman died in Washington, DC, in 2015.
Historical
On March 30, 1981, John W. Hinckley, Jr., attempted to assassinate United States President Ronald Reagan outside of the Hilton Hotel in Washington, D.C. Hinckley wounded Regan with a bullet that ricocheted off of the presidential limousine. Hinckely also wounded Secret Service Agent Timothy McCarthy, police officer Thomas Delahanty, and press secretary James Brady. In 1982, Hinckley was found not guilty by reason of insanity and was confined to St. Elizabeths Hospital in Washington, D.C. until his release in 2016. The trial led to significant alterations in the law regarding the insanity defense in criminal trials. Prior to 1984, defendants could be found not guilty by reason of insanity if it could be shown that, because of mental disease, they could not tell the difference between right and wrong or could not control themselves well enough to obey the law. In 1984, in direct response to the Hinckley verdict, Congress passed the Comprehensive Crime Control Act, which set a higher bar for the insanity defense in federal courts. Under this new law, lack of control was no longer a defense.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains trial transcripts, pleadings, pre-trial motions, photographs, correspondence, and personal writings. The materials date from 1981-1989. These are the records of Roger M. Adelman, who served as the senior prosecutor for the United States attorney's office during the trial of John W. Hinckley, Jr. The records are related to this trial and Hinckley's attempted assassination of United States President Ronald Reagan.
Actions and defenses; Insanity defense; Insanity (Law); Evidence; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation; Legislation; Knight, Paul; Cardozo, Mike; Reagan, Ronald; Hinckley, John W., Jr.; Bundy, Ted; Foster, Jodie
- Legal documents, 1981-1989; 1981-1982; Series 1; 10.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  The materials of this series include transcripts of trial proceedings, official reports of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), correspondence, and photographs. The series has been divided into four sub-series: Trial proceedings, Prosecutive reports, Hinckley chron file II 1982-1987, and Photographs. They range in date from 1981-1989 and include legal documents related to the trial of John W. Hinckley, Jr., in his assassination attempt of United States President Ronald Reagan.
  Arrangement
  Arranged into 4 subseries: Trial proceedings, Prosecutive reports, Hinckley chron file II 1982-1987, and Photographs.
  - Trial proceedings, 1981-1989; 1981-1982; series 1 subseries 1; 6.5 Linear Feet
    The materials of this sub-series include pleadings, transcripts of trial proceedings, memoranda, motions, and depositions related to the trial of John W. Hinckley, Jr., in the attempted assassination of United States President Ronald Reagan. The items range in date from 1981-1989.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr. Volume 1 [1/3], 1981-1982; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr. Volume 1 [2/3], 1981-1982; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr. Volume 1 [3/3], 1981-1982; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr. Volume 2 [1/3], 1981-1982; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr. Volume 2 [2/3], 1981-1982; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr. Volume 2 [3/3], 1981-1982; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - United States v. J. Hinkcley, 1981 March-September; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2A, Folder 1)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley, 1981 October 23; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2A, Folder 2)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley [1/3], 1981 October 26; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2A, Folder 3)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley [2/3], 1981 October 26; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2A, Folder 4)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley [3/3], 1981 October 26; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2A, Folder 5)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley [1/2], 1981 October 27; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2A, Folder 6)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley [2/2], 1981 October 27; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2A, Folder 7)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley, 1981 November 4; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 1)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley, 1981 November 6; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 2)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley, 1981 November 13; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 3)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley, 1981 November 25; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., 1981 December 14; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., 1981 December 21; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 6)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., 1982 February 25; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 7)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., 1982 March 24; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 8)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., 1982 March 29; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 9)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., 1982 March 30; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 10)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., 1982 April 7, 19; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2B, Folder 11)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Jodie Foster Deposition, 1982 April 7; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2C, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Jodie Foster Deposition, 1982 April 13; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2C, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., 1982 April 22; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2C, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., 1982 April 23; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2C, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., 1982 April 26; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2C, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 1, 1982 April 27; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2C, Folder 6)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 2, 1982 April 27; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2C, Folder 7)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 3, 1982 April 28; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2C, Folder 8)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 4, 1982 April 28; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2D, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 5, 1982 April 29; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2D, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 6, 1982 April 29; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2D, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 7, 1982 April 30; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2D, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 8, 1982 April 30; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3A, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr. [1/2], 1982 May 1; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3A, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr. [2/2], 1982 May 1; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3A, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 9, 1982 May 3; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3A, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volumes 10-11, 1982 May 3; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3A, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volumes 12-13, 1982 May 4; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3A, Folder 6)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 14, 1982 May 4; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3A, Folder 7)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 15, 1982 May 5; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3A, Folder 8)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 16, 1982 May 5; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3B, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 17, 1982 May 6; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3B, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 18, 1982 May 6; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3B, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 19, 1982 May 7; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3B, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 20, 1982 May 7; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3B, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 21, 1982 May 10; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3B, Folder 6)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 22, 1982 May 10; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3B, Folder 7)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 23, 1982 May 11; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3C, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 24, 1982 May 11; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3C, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 25, 1982 May 12; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3C, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 26, 1982 May 12; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3C, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 27, 1982 May 13; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3C, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 28, 1982 May 13; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3C, Folder 6)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 29, 1982 May 14; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3C, Folder 7)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 30, 1982 May 14; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3D, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 31, 1982 May 17; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3D, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 32, 1982 May 17; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3D, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 33, 1982 May 18; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3D, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 34, 1982 May 18; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4A, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 35 [1/2], 1982 May 19; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4A, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 35 [2/2], 1982 May 19; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4A, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 37, 1982 May 20; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4A, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 38, 1982 May 20; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4A, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 39, 1982 May 21; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4A, Folder 6)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 40, 1982 May 21; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4A, Folder 7)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 41, 1982 May 24; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4A, Folder 8)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 42, 1982 May 24; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4B, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 43, 1982 May 25; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4B, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 44, 1982 May 25; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4B, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 45, 1982 May 26; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4B, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 46, 1982 May 26; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4B, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 47, 1982 May 27; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4B, Folder 6)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 48, 1982 May 27; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4B, Folder 7)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 49, 1982 May 28; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4C, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volumes 50-51, 1982 June 1; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4C, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 52, 1982 June 2; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4C, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 53, 1982 June 2; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4C, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 54, 1982 June 3; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4C, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 55, 1982 June 3; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4C, Folder 6)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 56, 1982 June 4; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4C, Folder 7)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 57, 1982 June 4; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4C, Folder 8)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 58, 1982 June 7; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4D, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 59, 1982 June 7; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4D, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 60, 1982 June 8; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4D, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 61, 1982 June 8; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4D, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 62, 1982 June 9; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5A, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 63, 1982 June 9; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5A, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 64, 1982 June 10; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5A, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 65, 1982 June 10; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5A, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 66, 1982 June 11; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5A, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 67, 1982 June 11; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5A, Folder 6)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 68, 1982 June 12; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5A, Folder 7)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 69, 1982 June 12; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5A, Folder 8)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 70, 1982 June 14; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5B, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 71, 1982 June 14; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5B, Folder 2)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 72, 1982 June 15; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5B, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volumes 73-74, 1982 June 16; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5B, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 76, 1982 June 17; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5B, Folder 5)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 77, 1982 June 17; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5B, Folder 6)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volumes 78-79, 1982 June 18; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5B, Folder 7)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 81, 1982 June 18; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5B, Folder 8)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volume 82, 1982 June 19; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5C, Folder 1)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Volumes 85-87, 1982 August 6; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5C, Folder 2)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley, 1984-1987; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5C, Folder 3)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley, 1987 April; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5C, Folder 4)
    - United States v. J. Hinckley, 1987; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5C, Folder 5)
    - Hinckley 1987 Proceedings, Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5C, Folder 6)
    - Hinckley 1987 Proceedings, Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5C, Folder 7)
    - Hinckley Hearings and Pleadings [1/3], 1989 September; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5D, Folder 1)
    - Hinckley Hearings and Pleadings [2/3], 1989 September; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5D, Folder 2)
    - Hinckley Hearings and Pleadings [3/3], 1989 September; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5D, Folder 3)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Criminal No. 81-306, Index of Boxed Materials [1/2], 1981-1989; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5D, Folder 4)
    - United States v. John W. Hinckley, Jr., Criminal No. 81-306, Index of Boxed Materials [2/2], 1981-1989; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5D, Folder 5)
  - Prosecutive reports, 1981; Series 1 Subseries 2; 1.5 Linear Feet
    The materials of this sub-series include official reports of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or prosecutive reports, related to the trial of John W. Hinckley, Jr., in the attempted assassination of United States President Ronald Reagan. There are 9 bound volumes, including 4 reports and 5 appendices. The materials date to 1981.
    - Prosecutive Report: John Warnock Hinckley, Jr. Attempted Assassination of Ronald Reagan, President of the United States, March 30, 1981, Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6A, Volume 1)
    - Prosecutive Report: John Warnock Hinckley, Jr. Attempted Assassination of Ronald Reagan, President of the United States, March 30, 1981, Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6A, Volume 2)
    - Prosecutive Report: John Warnock Hinckley, Jr. Attempted Assassination of Ronald Reagan, President of the United States, March 30, 1981, Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6A, Volume 3)
    - Prosecutive Report: John Warnock Hinckley, Jr. Attempted Assassination of Ronald Reagan, President of the United States, March 30, 1981, Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6B, Volume 1)
    - Prosecutive Report: John Warnock Hinckley, Jr. Attempted Assassination of Ronald Reagan, President of the United States, March 30, 1981, Appendix A. Photographs-Laboratory, Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6B, Volume 2)
    - Prosecutive Report: John Warnock Hinckley, Jr. Attempted Assassination of Ronald Reagan, President of the United States, March 30, 1981, Appendix A. Other Law Enforcement Agency Reports, Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6B, Volume 3)
    - Prosecutive Report: John Warnock Hinckley, Jr. Attempted Assassination of Ronald Reagan, President of the United States, March 30, 1981, Appendix B. Additional Writings of John W. Hinckley, Jr., Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6B, Volume 4)
    - Prosecutive Report: John Warnock Hinckley, Jr. Attempted Assassination of Ronald Reagan, President of the United States, March 30, 1981, Appendix D. Photographs - Park Central Hotel, Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6B, Volume 5)
    - Prosecutive Report: John Warnock Hinckley, Jr. Attempted Assassination of Ronald Reagan, President of the United States, March 30, 1981, Appendix F. Writings of Subject, Series 1 Subseries 2 (Box 6B, Volume 6)
  - Hinckley chron file II 1982-1987, Series 1 Subseries 3; 0.25 Linear Feet
    The materials of this sub-series include correspondence, reports, memoranda, memos, and articles related to John W. Hinckley Jr.'s attempted assassination of United States President Ronald Reagan. The materials range in date from 1982-1987.
    Arranged in the order in which it was received.
    - Hinckley Chron File II 1982-1987 [1/3], Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Hinckley Chron File II 1982-1987 II [2/3], Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Hinckley Chron File II 1982-1987 [3/3], Series 1 Subseries 3 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1981-1982; Series 1 Subseries 4; 2 Linear Feet
    The materials of this sub-series include oversized photographs that are mounted on cardboard and were likely used as trial exhibits in the case of John W. Hinckley, Jr., in the attempted assassination of United States President Ronald Reagan. The materials range in date from 1981 to 1982.
    Arranged in no particular order.
    - Crime Scene Photographs, 1981; Series 1 Subseries 4 (Box 8)
    - Crime Scene Photographs, 1981; Series 1 Subseries 4 (Box 9)
- Personal writings, 1981-1986; Series 2; 0.25 Linear Feet
  The materials of this series include the personal writings of John W. Hinckley, Jr., as well as correspondence between Hinckley and serial killer Ted Bundy. They range in date from 1981-1986.
  - The Diary of A Person We All Know, 1981-1982; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Ted Bundy [1/2], 1986; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Ted Bundy [2/2], 1986; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 3)